Guide to the Hubert Oliver Jenkins Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hubert Oliver Jenkins papers
1902-1948
SC0390
Jenkins, Hubert Oliver.
1.75 Linear feet
Papers document his academic career at Stanford and include drawings and notes from science classes, 1903-1907; notes from a class at Hopkins Marine Station, 1932; and notes, maps, financial accounts, and a diary from his doctoral research on meadow mice in Benwood Meadows, Eldorado County, California, 1937-1939. Other items include his high school notebook, reprints, maps, and an abstract of his dissertation.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Hubert Oliver Jenkins, born in Terre Haute, Indiana, in 1885, was the son of Stanford. professor Oliver P. Jenkins. He received his A.B. in zoology from Stanford. in 1907 and his M.S. in biology and public health from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. After 1931 he taught in the geology and natural history department at Sacramento Junior College in Sacramento, CA. Jenkins COIl"pleted his Ph.D. in biology at Stanford. in 1940. In 1958 he published Glaciation in Big Bend National Park, Texas (Sacramento: Sacramento state College Foundation).
Description of the Collection
This collection primarily documents Jenkins' academic career at Stanford University. Included are drawings and notes from science classes, 1903-1907; notes from a class at Hopkins Marine Station, 1932; and notes, maps, financial accounts, and a diary from his doctoral research on meadow mice in Benwood Meadows, Eldorado County, california, 1937-1939. other items include his high school notebook, reprints, maps, and an abstract of his dissertation.
Access Terms
Jenkins, Hubert Oliver.; Benwood Meadows (Eldorado County, Calif.).; Maps.; Microtus.; Zoology --Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Notebook-Palo Alto High School-1902-03, 1902-1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes-Invertebrate Zoology-Stanford-1903-04, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes-Botany 3 and 6-Stanford-1904-05, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes-Botany 3-Stanford-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notes-Vertebrate Embryology-Stanford-1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes--Comparative Anatomy-Stanford-1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notes-Invertebrate Embryology-Stanford-1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bird feathers. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes-Algae Course-Hopkins Marine station--surnmer 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Benwood Notes-1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Benwood Notes--1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Benwood Notes--1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation Abstract-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Animal Distribution Table-Photos--1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Article Reprints (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - USGS California Pyramid Peak sheet (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eldorado National Forest Maps (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Benwood Meadow Maps (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Echo Summit Maps (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Boy Scouts Maps (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Unlabeled Maps (Box 3, Folder 4)